Amit Chambial

☐ devaman | in amit-chambial | ⊕ devaman.dev | ✓ chambialamit@gmail.com | ■ 9882927803

Summary

Reactjs / Nodejs / Vuejs is my field of expertise. I have built some projects which got featured in ProductHunt.I love building cool things! These 'Cool things' include NPM Packages, React Libs, and a lot of random things that I built for fun. .

EDUCATION

2015 - 2019	Bachelor's of Technology at NIT Hamirpur	(GPA: 8.92/10.0)
2015	Class 12th CBSE Board	(95%)
2013	Class 10th CBSE Board	(GPA: 9.80/10.0)

Work Experience

Software Developer II Netomi

Mar 2022 - Present

- Optimized the application by removing unnecessary api calls, removing watchers, adding webpack compression etc
- Worked on Docker Migration for our product.
- Created POC for enabling Real time Notification using RabittMQ and Web Push
- Intergrated Kafka with Nodejs
- Worked on creating Generic Components which can be scaled using config
- Mentoring team-mates
- Working on migrating app to Vue 3 and Webpack 5

Software Developer *Netomi*

Jun 2021 - Mar 2022

- Worked on AI Configuration Dashboard (link)
- Created a Micro-Frontend POC with React in Vue is with Routing. (blog)
- Integerated Redis Cache with Nodejs Server for storing logged out jwt token and Rate limiter
- Tech Vuejs, Nodejs, Docker, Redis, Microfrontend

Software Engineer JP Morgan Chase and Co.

Jul 2019 - Jun 2021

- Working on a dashboard which automates the encryption/unencryption for data at rest
- Finding a manual task and automating it.
- Working on CI/CD for our application.
- Working on AppDynamics and APICA for Monitoring.
- Working on .NET Core, React.js, Nodejs etc

Technology Analyst Intern JP Morgan Chase and Co.

May 2018 - Jul 2018

- Worked on JAVA(Springboot), and React is .
- Worked on BDD and TDD Testing for the given project

SKILLS

HTML, Javascript, Css, Reactis, Nodejs, Vuejs, Docker, Kafka, Redis, React Native, Webpack

Personal Projects

Perfecto Link to Demo

A HTML Template built using TailWind.css

ismy.institute Link to Demo

Create your own ismy.institute page and show off your college talent to outer world. Share articles and events on our site to attract more audience. Nextjs,Nodejs, Mongodb

BuildMyResume Link to Demo

Live Resume Builder (Reactjs, Nodejs, MongoDB)

ReadLine Js

Link to Demo

Javascript Library to inject a readline approximation bar at the top of the page. Deployed on npm.

CryptoCards Link to Demo

Anyone can share crypto news to the world. I call these posts as cards. React JS, Firebase

VoteChain Link to Demo

A decentralized way of creating a poll. Reactjs, Solc, Solidity

Redirecto Link to Demo

URL Shortner Made during Hackathon. (Reactjs, Nodejs, Mongo DB)

Complaint Link to Demo

A decentralized way of registering a complaint. Solidity, Reactjs, Truffle

Course Miner Github (private)

Making course from youtube. Track your progress. Ruby on Rails, SQL, HTML, SASS

CERTIFICATIONS

React JS (12/2017 - 12/2017)

Udemy Course. Learnt ReactJs, Redux, Routing, React Native

Web Development Course (06/2017 - 08/2017)

Coding Ninjas. Learnt Ruby on Rails, Html, CSS, Mysql.

HACKATHONS

Hack In The North(IIITA)

HackOnHills(NITH)

JPMC Hackathon (JP Morgan)